Guide to the William Knowles Papers
Stanford University. Libraries.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
William Knowles papers
1874-1916
SC0839
Knowles, William.
1 Linear feet
Knowles' papers include his letters to his parents, 1888 and 1893, one of which recounts his track record at Stanford; a few undated compositions; several pencil sketches of Stanford scenes, 1894; his business cards; and a booklet of images of buildings he designed. Family papers include miscellaneous letters, 1907-16 and undated; a book of poetry by his step-father Tom Veitch, 1906; a reference letter for Jean Montgomery Duncan, 1902; baby book for Duncan Knowles (son of William and Jean Duncan Knowles), 1906; scrapbook kept by a Duncan relative largely containing clippings of poems with some items re family members, 1874-1906; and photographs, largely unidentified.
Department of Special Collections and University Archives Green Library 557 Escondido Mall Stanford, CA 94305-6064 Email: specialcollections@stanford.edu Phone: (650) 725-1022 URL: http://library.stanford.edu/spc
Administrative Information
Information about Access
This collection is open for research.
Biographical/Historical Sketch
William Andrew Knowles, Jr., attended Stanford University from 1892 to 1895 and was on the track team. He went on to have a career as an architect in the Bay Area. He married Jean Montgomery Duncan in 1905.
Description of the Collection
Knowles' papers include his letters to his parents, 1888 and 1893, one of which recounts his track record at Stanford; a few undated compositions; several pencil sketches of Stanford scenes, 1894; his business cards; and a booklet of images of buildings he designed. Family papers include miscellaneous letters, 1907-16 and undated; a book of poetry by his step-father Tom Veitch, 1906; a reference letter for Jean Montgomery Duncan, 1902; baby book for Duncan Knowles (son of William and Jean Duncan Knowles), 1906; scrapbook kept by a Duncan relative largely containing clippings of poems with some items re family members, 1874-1906; and photographs, largely unidentified.
Access Terms
Knowles, William.; Stanford University -- General subdivision--Sports.;; Stanford University. Department of Athletics.; Veitch, Tom.; Veitch, Tom.
Collection Contents
- Papers
  - Letters to his parents, 1888-1893 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Compositions by Knowles (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Pencil sketches by Knowles, 1894 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Miscellany (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Family letters, miscellaneous, 1907-16 and undated (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Veitch, Tom, "Out-O'-Door Verses", 1906 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Reference letter for Jean M. Duncan, 1902 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Baby Book for Duncan Knowles, 1906 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Photo of Duncan Knowles, circa 1908 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Family photos (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Duncan scrapbook (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Photos from Duncan scrapbook (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - William Knowles, Architect--booklet of images of buildings by Knowles (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Oversized family photos (Box 2, Folder 2)